A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - License Returns, 1802-1881
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts - License Returns, 1802-1881
The Library of Virginia
APA 454
XX cu. ft. (XX boxes)
Virginia Auditor of Public Accounts (1776-1928)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Auditor of Public Accounts in 1913.
Biographical Information
Certain occupations were subjected to license fees as early as 1782, and often are found listed in personal property tax books. In addition, tax commissioners were required to file with the auditor returns that identified licensees as merchants, peddlers, tavern and ordinary keepers, owners of stallions and jackasses, physicians, lawyers, dauguerrian artists (photographers), and so forth. The occupations taxed vary and several years of returns are missing, as are some county returns for certain years.
Scope and Content
License returns, 1802-1881, are arranged chronologically and alphabetically by county/city thereunder. Lists include name, date and amount of fee paid. These returns cover the years 1802, 1804, 1806-1839, 1841-1855, 1858, 1860-1863, 1866, 1870-1872, 1874-1876, 1878, 1881. The year date of the return typically includes part of previous year.
These records are part of Auditor of Public Accounts. Administration of State Government: Revenue Assessment and Collection - Fees and Licenses.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically and alphabetically by county/city thereunder..
Contents List
- License Returns, 1802-1881.
  - License returns: Merchant - Amelia, 1802. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Merchant - Dinwiddie, 1804. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - Richmond City, 1804-1806. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - Henrico/Richmond City, 1805-1806. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - A-G, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - H-O, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - P-W, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - A-H, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - J-W, 1807. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - A-C, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - D-G, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - H-K, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - L-M, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - N-O, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - P-R, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - S-Y, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - A-F, 1808. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - G-I, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - J-M, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - N-P, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - R-Y, 1808. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - A-E, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - F-K, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - L-O, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - P-R, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - S-Y, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern, 1809. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - A-C, 1810. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - F-I, 1810. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - License returns: Hawker/Peddler - K-W, 1810. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - A-E, 1810. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - F-I, 1810. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - J-N, 1810. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - O-R, 1810. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - S-Y, 1810. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - A-C, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - D-G, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - H-L, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - M-P, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - R-W, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Merchant - A-C, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Merchant - D-G, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - License returns: Merchant - H-L, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - License returns: Merchant - M-N, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - License returns: Merchant - O-R, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - License returns: Merchant - S-W, 1811. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - A-C, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - F-H, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - K-N, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - O-Y, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern -A-C, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - E-J, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - K-P, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - R-Y, 1812. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - A-B, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - C-F, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - G-H, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - I-L, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - M-N, 1813. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - O-R, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler and Ordinary Tavern - S-Y, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - A-B, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - C-E, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - F-G, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - H-K, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - L-M, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - N-O, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - P-R, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - S-W, 1813. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - A-C, 1814. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - E-H, 1814. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - I-O, 1814. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - License returns: Ordinary/Tavern - P-W, 1814. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - A-G, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - H-N, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - License returns: Merchant/Peddler - P-Y, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - A-B, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - C-F, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - G-I, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - J-L, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - M-N, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - O-R, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - License returns: Attorney/Physician - S-Y, 1814. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - License returns - A-B, 1815. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - License returns - C-E, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - License returns - F-G, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - License returns - H-J, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - License returns - K-L, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - License returns - M-N, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - License returns - O-P, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - License returns - R-S, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - License returns - T-Y, 1815. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - License returns - A-C, 1816. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - License returns - D-G, 1816. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - License returns - H-K, 1816. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - License returns - L-O, 1816. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - License returns - P-R, 1816. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - License returns - S-Y, 1816. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - License returns - A-C, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - License returns - D-G, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - License returns - H-K, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - License returns - L-O, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - License returns - P-R, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - License returns - S-W, 1817. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - License returns - A-C, 1818. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - License returns - D-G, 1818. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - License returns - H-K, 1818. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - License returns - L-O, 1818. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - License returns - P-R, 1818. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - License returns - S-Y, 1818. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - License returns - A-D, 1819. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - License returns - E-G, 1819. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - License returns - H-K, 1819. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - License returns - L-P, 1819. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - License returns - R-Y, 1819. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - License returns - A-C, 1820. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - License returns - D-G, 1820. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - License returns - H-J, 1820. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - License returns - K-L, 1820. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - License returns - M-O, 1820. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - License returns - P-R, 1820. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - License returns - S-Y, 1820. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - License returns - A-B, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - License returns - C-E, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - License returns - F-G, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - License returns - H-K, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - License returns - L-M, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - License returns - N-O, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - License returns - P, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - License returns - R-S, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - License returns - T-W, 1821. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - License returns - A-B, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - License returns - C-E, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - License returns - F-G, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - License returns - H-J, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - License returns - K-L, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - License returns - M, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - License returns - N-O, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - License returns - P, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - License returns - R-S, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - License returns - T-Y, 1822. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - License returns - A-B, 1823. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - License returns - C-E, 1823. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - License returns - F-G, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - License returns - H-J, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - License returns - K-L, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - License returns - M, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - License returns - N-O, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - License returns - P, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - License returns - R-S, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - License returns - T-Y, 1823. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - License returns - A, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - License returns - B, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - License returns - C, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - License returns - D, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - License returns - E, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - License returns - F, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - License returns - G, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - License returns - H, 1824. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - License returns - I-J, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - License returns - K, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - License returns - L, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - License returns - M, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - License returns - N, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - License returns - O, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - License returns - P, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - License returns - R, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - License returns - S, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - License returns - T, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - License returns - W, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - License returns - Y, 1824. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - License returns - A, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - License returns - B, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - License returns - C, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - License returns - Dinwiddie/Petersburg, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - License returns - E, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - License returns - F, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - License returns - G, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - License returns - H, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - License returns - Henrico/Richmond, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - License returns - I-J, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - License returns - K, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - License returns - L, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - License returns - Ma-Mi, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - License returns - Mo, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - License returns - Na-Ni, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - License returns - No, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - License returns - O, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - License returns - Pa-Po, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - License returns - Pr, 1825. (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - License returns - R, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - License returns - S, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - License returns - Spotsylvania/Fredericksburg, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - License returns - T, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - License returns - W, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - License returns - Y, 1825. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - License returns - A, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - License returns - Ba-Bo, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - License returns - Br-Bu, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - License returns - C, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - License returns - Campbell/Lynchburg, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - License returns - Dinwiddie/Petersburg, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - License returns - E, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - License returns - F, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - License returns - G, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - License returns - H, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - License returns - Henrico/Richmond, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - License returns - I-J, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - License returns - K, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - License returns - L, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - License returns - Ma-Mi, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - License returns - Mo, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - License returns - Na-Ni, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - License returns - No, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - License returns - Norfolk County/Norfolk Borough, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - License returns - O, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - License returns - Pa-Po, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - License returns - Pr, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - License returns - R, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - License returns - S, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - License returns - Spotsylvania/Fredericksburg, 1826. (Box 14, Folder 31)